Donna Buzar

IT Project Manager

Kent, WA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Donna-Buzar/ed53889fbb6253bd

Donna has 10+ years of IT project management experience with extensive breadth of skills, including business, functional, and systems analysis across many enterprise applications and systems. With a career stemming from experience as a developer, Donna has the ability to plan and lead IT projects, ensure business requirements are met, and successfully lead teams with both agile and traditional project methods.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Project Manager

Seattle Public Schools - Seattle, WA -

February 2017 to September 2017

Consultant through TekSystems

Provided project planning and oversight, and management of requirements for a vendor hosted SAP PowerSchool Online Registration project to replace a paper forms centered process. The phased project introduced online new student enrollment, and enabled parents to update student information throughout the year. This core enterprise system serves over 100K families.

- 1. Participated in vendor engagement process, worked toward accomplishing configuration SOW
- 2. Developed project planning deliverables; project approach, task list, timeline, training, test plan, and communications plan
- 3. Managed implementations in phases (blended Agile/Waterfall project methodology)
- 4. Worked with stakeholders to identify and document requirements, workflows, and align standard processes
- 5. Worked with vendor to understand vendor requirements and implementation method
- 6. Coordinated collaborative work sessions with vendor for team
- 7. Provided oversight for vendor solution build and configuration activities
- 8. Reported project status to stakeholders on a bi-weekly basis
- 9. Coordinated implementation of vendor solutions with IT partners; data extracts, file loads, system setup
- 10. Wrote communications and procedural materials for public and internal consumption

IT Project Manager

City of Tacoma -

August 2016 to January 2017

Consultant through InfoReliance Corp.

Provided project planning and analysis for a \$1.2 million project already in progress to install and configure a SharePoint / Gimmalsoft Records Management solution. Managed a Vendor team of 4 consultants who completed the design, configuration, and development of a custom automated records management solution for a City Department's complex business workflow including integration with SAP case management records.

- Worked with PMO staff and business unit stakeholders to review current project plan, charter, and schedule in support of project status analysis
- Developed updated project plan using MS Project to re-focus efforts on project deliverables and critical path activities
- Improved communications of project work and coordination between Vendor and City teams by introducing Daily Team Standup and Weekly Team Planning meetings
- Helped Vendor team resolve issues and provide consultation to move the project forward
- Assisted with development of Team workshop to reduce complexity of combining efforts of RIMTech consultant, InfoReliance consultants, and City of Tacoma team
- Worked with City PMO staff to help them understand the project status and determine project suspension outcome

IT Project Manager

IRON MOUNTAIN -

May 2014 to January 2016

Consultant through Beacon Hill Staffing Group

Provided project planning and oversight, and management of IT requirements for a \$2.2 million Vendor-based conversion project to update an internally developed system's code base from VB6 to C# and HTML5. The multi-year project eliminated the technical debt of VB6 and transformed the forms-based system to a web application. This core enterprise system was developed for use by 3200 internal Operations staff-members daily.

- Worked with operations and business unit stakeholders to develop project plans, charters, and schedules in support of business needs
- Performed project budget and schedule performance analysis using Microsoft Dynamics and JIRA Sprint reporting tools to ensure project objectives were met
- Used Excel templates to define, document, and prioritize project enhancement requests, plan resources, generate timelines, communicate, build consensus, and gain individual commitment for deliverables
- Coordinated multiple high priority enhancement and hot fix releases along-side code conversion project
- Managed status and key performance metrics reporting for project stakeholders and executive leadership audiences on a weekly, monthly, and ad-hoc basis
- Coordinated Change Management plans with Change Advisory Board (CAB), Enterprise Communications, and Operations teams
- · Helped the team deliver day-to-day project activities by actively identifying issues, and removing obstacles

IT Project Manager

NORDSTROM INC -

September 2011 to October 2013

Planned and provided project oversight for implementation of SuccessFactors Employee Performance Management System, integrating system functionality with Oracle Human Resources (HRMS). The new system provided the administrative tools that standardized employee performance measures spanning multiple divisions, and launch and manage performance reviews for 65,000 employees across performance review

seasons. The \$2.5 million project completed successfully by meeting the expectations of the sponsor, delivering under budget, and launching performance reviews on time.

- Participated in vendor procurement process, coordinated with legal, developed SOW
- Directed, reviewed, and approved business requirements gathering, functional specification development, and technical specification development
- Managed and controlled development team's day-to-day project activities, issues, risks, quality, and budget
- Developed solution approach strategy documentation to capture details of challenges including pros and cons, develop and propose solutions, and facilitate decisions
- Coordinated implementation plans with Change Advisory Board (CAB), Operations, and Software Assurance team (SAT) to ensure business continuity and minimize business disruptions during system implementation
- Prepared and participated in monthly budget and resource forecasting activities
- Completed in house training in Agile Project Methodology (SCRUM)
- Managed implementations in phases (blended Agile/Waterfall project methodology)

IT Project Manager

KENT SCHOOL DISTRICT -

October 1995 to August 2009

Planned and managed implementation projects such as a Purchasing Card System that integrated system functionality with Oracle Government Financials, and a Records Management System in conjunction with retirement of a legacy Student Information System.

- Developed project planning deliverables; project approach, task list, timeline, and communications plan
- Worked with stakeholders to identify and document requirements, test planning, and implementation
- Developed knowledge of people change management and organizational change to anticipate risk and mitigate with training and transition plans
- Lead and mentored test teams of 2 5 persons; Organized and lead data entry teams of 25-30 persons
- Reported project status to stakeholders
- Coordinated implementation of vendor solutions with IT partners

Business Analyst

- Adept at learning new business areas; provided information systems support to departments such as Finance and Accounting, Special Education and Programs, and Business Administration
- Worked with stakeholders to help them understand effects of technology choices
- Researched, analyzed, and applied government regulations and guidelines
- Applied knowledge of process improvement tools and techniques; Conducted work sessions with stakeholders to document business processes
- Performed gap analysis; developed as-is and to-be documentation
- Developed business requirements for interfaces, UI, and reports for enhancements, ad hoc requests, and upgrades
- Planned and performed UAT for many system enhancements and implementations

Systems Analyst

- Performed systems analysis and developed functional requirements for interfaces, UI, and reporting for enhancements, issue resolution, ad hoc requests, upgrades, and system patches
- Used problem solving skills and analysis of data and system behavior in support of Oracle Government Financials applications and Finance & Accounting business customers

- Performed configurations for vendor-based system implementations
- System administration for Records Management System

Sr. Programmer/Analyst

- Performed technical analysis of business requirements and functional specifications, and developed technical specifications
- Developed solutions for system enhancements, ad hoc requests, reporting, and issue resolution using PL/ SQL, SQL*Plus, Crystal Reports, and Java
- Used problem solving skills to perform root cause analysis
- Planned and Performed unit and system testing to validate developed solutions
- Coordinated implementation of developed solutions

EDUCATION

Project Management Certification in Project Management

University of Washington Extension - Seattle, WA

January 2010 to August 2010

LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/in/donnabuzar

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

PMP

May 2011 to May 2020

Project Management Institute Certification

PMI-ACP

July 2016 to July 2019

Project Management Institute - Agile Certified Practitioner

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

ABILITIES TECHNICAL SKILLS

Project Management of Scope, Schedule, Budget, Risk, Issue Resolution, Quality, Integration, Staffing, and Communications

Project Management Software:

- Microsoft Project
- Open Workbench
- JIRA

Management of small, mid-sized, and large software enterprise software implementations Project Methodologies:

Traditional

• Agile

Collaborates effectively with internal and external groups; interacts with stakeholders, shared services teams, development team, QA team, etc.

Reporting Tools:

- Microsoft Dynamics
- Microstrategy
- Clarity

Strong Analytical and Problem Solving capabilities; recognizes requirements and issues that pass by many others

Issue Tracking Tools:

- JIRA
- Quality Center (QC)
- Team Foundation Server (TFS)

Effectively Communicates with both Technical and Non-Technical Audiences

Microsoft Office:

- Excel, Word, Outlook
- Visio, PowerPoint, SharePoint & Confluence

Management of multiple objectives/tasks concurrently to drive project progress

Teams Supported:

- On-site
- Near-shore
- Off-shore